# ANGELA PLANK

angelaplanknm@gmail.com | (505) 592-9268 | Waterflow, NM 87421

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a past career educator who had taught a myriad of grade levels for 13 years, I see myself as a lifetime learner who loves to read and grow as a person. At Shiprock High School I taught professional development meetings once a week with another Reading Specialist, as well as went into content area classrooms and taught Reading in others' classrooms. I served as a resource for teachers and a researcher and writer for the school in general. I'm good at communicating with others in all forms including technologically, designating duties, and guiding others to implement needed practices. Reading, technology, and traveling are my main passions in life. I love learning and am devoted to all aspects of education so I am willing to take additional classes or attend workshops as needed. Please email or give me a call to set up an appointment time to discuss services that I can provide.

### **SKILLS**

- Programming
- HTML 5
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Self-motivated
- Relationship building and management
- Technological instruction
- Experience with instructional design
- Interpersonal skills

- Strong written and verbal communicator
- Strong collaborator
- Computer proficient
- Blackboard software
- New Mexico Teaching Certificate with Elementary Education endorsement
- TESOL certification
- Teaching
- SMART Board aptitude

#### **WORK HISTORY**

**Language Arts Teacher** / Desert Horizon Elementary School - Phoenix, AZ. / 08.2001 - 05.2002

**Language Arts Teacher/Reading Specialist** / Shiprock High School - Shiprock, NM / 08.2002 - 05.2006

- Promoted effective verbal and written communication through listening, speaking, reading and writing practice.
- Utilized multimedia strategies and technology to convey information in fresh and interesting ways.

**Advanced Composition Teacher, Adjunct Faculty** / San Juan College - Farmington, NM / 01.2006 - 06.2006

 Sourced appropriate course materials to support variety of student learning needs and styles and deliver content in relevant, distinctive ways. • Displayed exemplary written and oral communication skills to meet learning styles and improve student learning.

**Language Arts Teacher** / Department Of Defense Education Activity-Europe - Naples, Italy / 08.2006 - 12.2009

- Cultivated relationships with parents for a complete support network.
- Promoted student growth by encouraging independent thinking, judgment and thought expression.

**Reading Specialist/Language Arts Teacher** / New Mexico School for the Blind and Visually Impaired - Alamogordo, NM / 11.2009 - 05.2011

- Performed student background reviews to ascertain learning deficiencies and strengths to develop tailored lessons based on student needs.
- Eliminated learning gaps and effectively instructed students by developing IEPs and using wide variety of teaching aids and motivational strategies.

English Teacher / Kirtland Middle School - Kirtland, NM / 01.2014 - 02.2015

- Assessed student performance, behavior and social development and devised improvement strategies for struggling children.
- Developed and implemented interesting and interactive learning media to increase student understanding of course materials.
- Integrated technology into classroom settings to engage students and diversify instruction.

**Teacher of the Visually Impaired** / Central Consolidated Schools - Shiprock, New Mexico / 08.2018 - 02.2019

#### **EDUCATION**

Lambda School--Coding Bootcamp - Online **Some College (No Degree)**: Web Development

New Mexico State University - Las Cruces, NM **Some College (No Degree)**: SPED & Technology

- Continuing education in Special Education
- Minored in Technology

Eastern New Mexico University - Portales, NM TESOL Endorsement

 Continuing education in Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages

Arizona State University - Tempe, AZ / 2002

**Master of Arts**: Curriculum & Instruction, Language and Literacy, Reading Education

University of New Mexico - Albuquerque, NM / 2000 **Bachelor of Arts**: Education, Communicative Arts Education, Secondary Language Arts

San Juan College - Farmington, NM General Education

GPA: 3.2, 108 credit hours--86 transfer credits to UNM)